

# Sukesh Batchu

### **Senior Frontend Developer**

Phone: (+49) 15144 818722 | Email: sukesh@sukeshkb.com | Linkedin: linked.com/sukeshkumarbatchu Address: Ahrweiler Str 26, 14197, Berlin, Germany

## **Summary**

A highly committed Frontend responsive UI developer with experience of more than 7 years in the field of software development. Diligent in formulating best coding practices for the Frontend Development using trending and robust Frontend frameworks.

# **Education**

### **Bachelor of Information Technology**

Osmania University, India 2006 to 2010

# **Key Skills**

#### Frontend

HTML5
CSS3
Bootstrap 4
Jquery, Jquery UI
Kendo UI
Angular Js, Angular 2+
Ext Js
Microsoft Sharepoint
React (Naive)
Electron JS

#### Tools

Sketch
Balsamiq
HPQC
Jira
BPM Tools
Tableau
Qlikview
Phonegap

#### Misc

Git
Webpack
Wordpress
Unbounce
Opentext
Scrum Agile Methodology

## **Experience**

1. Senior Frontend Developer @ KPMG

Berlin

05.2015 - Till Date

#### 2017 - Till date

- Development of responsive web applications using Sharepoint Customizations
- Delivered more than 7 applications working alone viz: Seat Planning, Event Registration Sites, Collaboration portals, Enterprise Search, Billing & Accounting Tool

#### 2015 - 2016

- Development of responsive Frontend User Interfaces in .net environment
- Part of developing Immigration Tool, Reporting tool for Global Mobility team in Tax
- 2. Senior Frontend Developer @ enadCo

Berlin

01.2015 - 04.2015

- Development of product user interfaces, maintaining the website, creation of Mobile User Interfaces
- 3. Senior Frontend Developer @ Accenture

India

01.2014 - 12.2014

- Involved in the development of Frontend for Bank of America Financial Products to migrate traditional UI to Rich Look Responsive UI using Ext JS
- 4. Software Developer @ Cognizant Technology Solutions Belgium, India 07.2010 12.2013

#### 2010 - 2012

 Worked on BPM Tool called Cordys, involved in creating workflows, implementation of Web services.

#### 2012 - 2013

 Part of Mobile Application Development team, involved in creating Hybrid Mobile Applications using Phonegap, Titanium Appcelerator

Sukesh Batchu Berlin, Germany